Francis Mwangi Njuguna

Software Developer

CONTACT

Phone: +254-715-219991

Email: francis.kanothe@gmail.com



https://github.com/mwanginjuguna



https://www.linkedin.com/in/francism-njuguna/

BIO

I am a passionate software developer and a writer. In 2019, I founded Paper Study service to assist student from across the world with private tutoring, research and writing assistance. This service introduced me to software development.

I started 5 years ago as a WordPress Developer and I have been a full-stack PHP Laravel developer for over 4 years. Through this time, I built and maintained 37 WordPress Websites and Two(2) Laravel Web Applications to manage clients for Paper Study. I retired Paper Study to focus on pure software development in 2023, and I have since built and collaborated to build more Laravel apps, and shipped many websites.

I have worked with teams, business owners, and collaborated with developers to complete Laravel & WP projects. My experience has enabled me to learn and use technologies such as PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, Linux, MySQL, AWS, Git, and JavaScript frameworks.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Laravel Developer | 2022-present

Senior Laravel Fullstack Developer at GamePlan Labs

- Developed, deployed, and maintained e-commerce & crm applications to manage over customers, payments, and orders;
- Integrated payment gateways in the above laravel applications
- Configured and deployed 8 websites and above applications to AWS, DigitalOcean, and Cpanel
- Partnered with teams @CodeBreeze to work on features & fix bugs on Laravel apps.

Fullstack Laravel Developer at PaperStudy

- Developed and maintained Two order system applications to manage over 280 clients, payments, five (5) experts, and 1700+ orders;
- Integrated PayPal and Stripe payment gateways through third-party APIs
- Implemented Frontend design using Vue.js 3 (Composition API) and Livewire
- · Used Git to manage app versions and deployments
- Deployed the Laravel Apps to cPanel and Google Cloud VM (Linux Server).

WordPress Developer at PaperStudy

- Developed and maintained of 37 WordPress websites.
- · Customize and manage Divi WordPress theme.
- Developed custom classic(1) and block(1) themes.
- Debugging and Fixing WordPress errors.
- Optimizing WordPress websites for SEO performance and page speed.
- · Optimizing caching, backups, MySQL database queries, and images.
- Deployment of WordPress websites on c-panel and shared hosting.

Francis Mwangi Njuguna

Software Developer

CONTACT

Phone: +254-715-219991

Email: francis.kanothe@gmail.com



https://github.com/mwanginjuguna



https://www.linkedin.com/in/francism-njuguna/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Continued)

Academic Tutor

(Freelance)

2018-2023

 Providing research, writing, and tutoring services to college, university, masters, and PhD students.

Teacher - Religion & Kiswahili

(Internship)

Matunda SA Secondary School

Jan 2019 - April 2019

• Collaborated with senior teachers to plan, evaluate and coordinate lessons and co-curricular activities in Kiswahili and CRE subjects.

SKILLS

- Software development
- Cloud Infrastructure & Deployment
- · Writing and Research
- · Teaching and Tutoring
- Copywriting

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent (writing/speaking)

Swahili - Native

EDUCATION

Moi University | 2015-2020

Bachelor of Arts with Education

• Religion and Kiswahili Specialization